Hello friends, in this video today, let's completely decode the Reissue 3.0 plan
offered by Nivabopa Health Insurance Company Limited
based on the brochure
.  The main highlight of this is
unlimited restoration, no room rent
limit, no co-payment, and
pre-existing diseases are covered from day one.
I will explain with real-life examples what this health insurance thing is that makes big claims like this.
Let's first look at the top benefits of this policy.
There are a total of four variants of this reissue policy: Black,
Elite, Select, and Classic, so
I'll just talk about the overall ones here.
I will cover these variants according to their importance in the middle, wherever they are
.  First, see Unlimited Summon
.  If you select the unlimited option in this reissue policy, please
clearly mention
in the brochure that there is no limit to the unlimited sum insured coverage in the policy year, but [Music] In practice, the
policy wordings as well as the
sequence conditions and exclusions in the schedule must be followed
.  Say for example, you have selected unlimited options even though your
hospital surgery bill is 50 lakhs
.  Also, if you
meet all the rules for eligibility, you have a
100% chance of settling your hospital bill
.  But if you
exceed the limits as well as non-admissible items, you will have to pay the out-
of-pocket expenses yourself
[music].  Or,
assuming you have not selected the unlimited option, then the
maximum limit for your policy is the base sum insured that the insurance company pays in that policy year,
so the claim will be paid only up to that amount
.  For example, if you have a health
insurance policy of ₹10 lakhs,
then normal claim payments
will be covered within these 10 lakhs.  The second one is
called Booster Plus, which is very
important.  If you
have some unclaimed sum insured in any year, it is
called a play-free year.  This booster plus creates an extra benefit by carrying forward the remaining sum insured
to the next year
.  It is said that the maximum base
sum can be carried forward up to 10 times to the institute
.
Let's look at a small example to understand this.  For
example, if you take out a policy for a sum assured of 10 lakhs,
you will not have any claims for 10 years.  This means that if
you now receive a claim in the 11th year,
your base sum insured for the 11th year would be
10,000,000, so that
amount plus the 1 crore amount added up to 10 years so far will add up to
your total sum insured of 1 crore 10
.  It is clearly mentioned in the brochure that this amount is eligible for your claim
.  I really like this future
.  In general, it would be great if there was a
carry forward option like this in claim-free years
.  This can be called a kind of cumulative bonus
.  Otherwise, keep in mind that it is
only available in the LED variant
.
This is ReSure Forever Unlimited Restoration.  Similarly,
Reassure Forever is a feature that supports the next claim, even if it is adjusted in the same policy year, after the first paid claim during the policy's lifetime, as a cover refill.  Let me explain
this with an example. Say
for example, your base sum
insured is 10 locks.  After the patient was
admitted to the hospital, the first
paid claim came in for ₹7,00,000
.  Assuming this is paid by the insurance company, the
Reinsurance Plus
option will now be triggered.  Let's say you still have a balance of
₹
3,000,000, and then
you get a second claim,
which is ₹1,200,000.
Now, how much will you pay for your claim amount?
You already have a balance sum
assured of ₹3,000, right?
That plus Reassure Forever will give you
base sum assured coverage up to ₹10,000,
right? So, your balance of 9 lock
amount will also be covered by Reassure Forever and the
insurance company
will also pay the total bill of 12 lock.  After this second claim, the
balance sum insured has
become zero. If the third claim of 11
lakhs comes again, then
you will
only have coverage up to 10 lakhs since you do not have any more base sum insured for that year through Reissue Forever.  This means you will have to
pay the remaining ₹1,00,000 yourself.   It is mentioned
very clearly in the brochure that
in this Reissue Forever, the insurance company will bear only up to the
base sum insured for any single flame. You have to
pay the remaining amount yourself. It is very important to
understand how the sum insured is consumed in this policy. The sequence of
paying health claims in this policy is like this:
first, your
base sum insured is covered, then
booster plus, then reissue
plus, and only then other benefits. It is very important to understand the money
flow structure rather than just planning by looking at the headline that says "unlimited"
.  How does the no room run limit
work in this policy?
Show the room options for the Classic Select Elite block variants in the brochure.
There are options like Any Room Covered in the block.  But
there is a strict rule in policy warding.  If you
take a higher room than the eligible room, you will have to
pay the proportionate amount yourself through a cash payment.  Furthermore, if you
breach the room category in an unwritten manner,
you will have to
pay a percentage-based co-payment depending on the variant
.  You also have
the facility to get a free health checkup every year
.  This makes preventive tracking
easier.  This is a good option.   It was
also mentioned that
alternative medicine in-patient
treatment like Ayurveda and homeopathy will also be covered under this policy
.  There are some other major
benefits, but all told, the video
length is likely to exceed one hour when I make it
.  So, just
skip the five-second video and
take a quick look at these other benefits.
Similarly,
who is eligible for this Reacher 3.0 plan offered by the Ivabupa company? The entry age for
this policy is 18 plus, which means
all adults are eligible. Similarly, the
policy type is individual and there
is also a family floater.  Similarly,
there is an option for one year, two years, three years, and more depending on the policy term.  They
also say that you can renew this policy for life.  This
registered policy
has some included options, ranging from ₹3,00,000 to ₹1 crore.  For those who export high coverage, it would be
better if there was an unlimited and unscheduled option.
This is very important as the core coverages of Reissure 3.0 offered by this insurance company include domiciliary hospitalization, i.e. home treatment,
as well as day treatments that can be completed without a 24-hour
stay
.  Covid treatment is
covered by the hospital daily cash per day, so it will range from 1000 to 4000 depending on the variant.  Likewise, road,
air ambulance, organ donor expenses, and
modern treatments are all
covered.  Along with this, it was also mentioned that personal
accident coverage can range from 5 lakhs
to 1 crore pieces, depending on the case
.
Similarly, in the cashless support, it is mentioned that
this consultation is only cashless,
which means that if you
call 48 hours before hospitalization, the treatment will be covered
at the recommended provider, that is,
at a network hospital
.  Similarly, they say that if you are admitted to an outside network hospital
within 24 hours of admission during an emergency,
rather than the recommended list,
then
copayment will be applicable
.  Also, keep in mind that this policy covers pre-
hospitalization medical expenses up
to 60 days and post-hospitalization medical
expenses up to 180 days,
but this limit is also
covered up to the sum insured
.  Similarly, the summary clearly mentions that IC charges are
also covered up to the insured amount, and
there is an option called Safeguard Plus for consumables or non-payable items, which clearly mentions that all non-payable items will be covered as per the
list
.  Next up
is Cash Back Plus.  This means a claim-free
year means a 10% discount on the first renewal premium,
5% for each renewal from the second renewal onwards, and an
extra
10% for every block of three claim-free years. You can use this accumulated amount to pay
non-payables such as OPD deductibles copay for premium
.  If you don't
understand any of the policy holdings I mentioned, let me make
two videos on this.
The link is in the description, take a
look.  Now, let me compare three ratios and tell you in one minute whether you should take this Nivabupa Reissue 3.0 policy or
not.
First, there is the solvency ratio, which
tells us about the financial strength of the company.
This is 1.67, 2.55, 3.03.  If this ratio is generally above the
minimum of 1.5, it is said that the company is
financially strong
.  If this ratio is good, then it's good
.  The claim settlement
ratio is
how many claims the company settles and sends out if it receives 100 claims.  This
claim settlement ratio is 90, 91,
and 92.  That means it will
improve as you study.  This is also good, okay, that's
fine.  If this ratio is
above 95%, then it's super.  But it's
okay, it's fine.  The claims
income ratio means that if the company collects Rs 1
in premium,
what percentage amount of it is spent on claims. It
is in this range of 54, 59, 61, which means that it
is in a somewhat healthy range, but we should keep checking
how the company pays claims in the future
.  If this ratio is generally
between 70 to 90%, it can be said that the
company pays claims in a healthy and balanced manner. Not bad, that's all. When it
comes to the complaints ratio, if a company
receives 10,000 claims, the
ratio that tells how many complaints it has received on average is
46 38 43.
This clearly indicates that there may be inconsistencies in the service length claims experience. It is better if it is below 10,
otherwise, this ratio can be said to be slightly
higher
.  Finally, the company's
solvency ratio is strong.
Similarly, the claim settlement ratio is also
good.  So you can consider this affordable
health insurance company
.  If not, I'm not saying that this is
not a super move. You
can consider it okay, it's just an average,
but if you have checked these ratios
now, I think it would be better to compulsorily check these ratios
at the renewal time and
continue the policy
.  So, if
you want good health insurance that meets all the ratios mentioned above, then
check out this video
.  If
you
liked this video about the health insurance offered by Adandi Niwabu, please like it and subscribe to our channel now for more such
banking and personal finance
videos
.  Thanks
for watching.